Over a hundred years ago,
humanity suddenly found itself
faced with a new predator.
They were far more powerful than humans.
Humanity was immediately pushed
to the brink of extinction.
The survivors built three walls:
Maria, Rose, and Sina.
There, they enjoyed a century of peace.
However...
Unknown are the names
of the flowers that have been trampled
Birds have fallen to the earth
and long for the wind
Prayers won't solve anything
Only the will to fight
can change the here and now!
O pigs who laugh at the resolve
to walk over corpses to move forward
Livestock complacency? False prosperity?
Give us the freedom of dying,
starving wolves!
The humiliation of being caged
is what triggers us to fight back
We hunters slaughter prey
beyond the castle walls,
consumed with surging bloodlust,
as our crimson bows and arrows
pierce scarlet holes into the twilight
Where the Left Arm Went
The Battle for Trost (5)
One reason so many soldiers died
in the Titans' attack on Trost
was the absence of the elite Survey Corps.
Only that morning,
they had embarked on
a reconnaissance mission beyond the walls.
They're here!
The main force of the Survey Corps!
Commander Erwin, kill the Titans for us!
Look, it's Captain Levi!
They say he's as strong as an entire brigade.
Shut up.
If they knew how fussy you are,
they wouldn't look at you
with such admiration.
The Titans are right outside...
What kind of Titan will we see this time?
It'd be so great if we saw an Aberrant!
We have one right here.
Huh? Where?
Right here.
Forward!
Survey outlying areas
and establish supply points
that would support a human advance.
Being entrusted with these missions,
the Survey Corps
receives the best
humanity has to offer.
The military genius of a select few
within their ranks has greatly
boosted their survival rate.
But even so, every excursion into Titan territory
costs over thirty percent of their troops.
The difference in strength
between humans and Titans is that great.
Just you wait...
It won't be long
before humanity wipes you out!
We'll be the ones to survive in the end!
Captain Levi will...
kill you all!
One to the right...
Two to the left.
Captain, I've brought reinforcements.
Petra, tend to the wounded soldiers below.
The rest of you, support the right flank.
I'll take care of the left.
Captain!
It's okay!
I won't hurt you.
So close!
Now it's my turn.
There!
See?
That didn't hurt, did it?
You all have...
the stupidest expressions.
Whoa.
Stay put.
Otherwise, it will get messy...
when I slice you.
Damn.
Filthy...
Captain,
the bleeding won't stop...
Captain...
What is it?
W-Was I able...
to help humanity?
Or will I die,
never having been of any use at all?
You have done a great deal.
And you will continue to do so.
The resolve you leave behind
will give me strength.
I promise you...
I will obliterate the Titans!
Captain...
He's gone.
Did he hear me to the very end?
Yes.
I'm sure he did.
Look.
He seems so at peace...
Very well, then.
Levi!
We're pulling back.
Pulling back?
We have yet to push ourselves to the limit.
Are my men dying for nothing?
The Titans are heading north, toward town.
Just like five years ago...
Something is happening in town.
The wall...
may have fallen.
Damn it!
Damn it...
It wasn't...
It wasn't supposed to be this way.
We had changed over the past five years...
We trained as hard as we could.
We thought long and hard.
It was all to defeat them...
So that they wouldn't take
anything else from us.
It's hot.
It's so hot...
Save me, Mother.
Mother?
Mother...
Save...
Why did this happen?
Why do they take everything from us?
Our lives.
Our dreams...
Why?
Damn it all! Damn it! Damn it!
I won't give up!
I'll eliminate them all...
Every single Titan!
I'll kill them myself!
I'll wipe them off the face
of the earth.
Every single one!
More...
Kill more!
I want to kill...
Kill...
more...
I'll kill them all.
Eren?
Eren!
Eren, can you move?
Can you understand what I'm saying?
Tell them everything you know.
I'm sure they'll understand!
Armin?
Hear that?
He said, "I'll kill them all!"
Yes, I heard him.
He's going to devour us.
What are they all talking about?
Are those blades pointed at us?
Those blades are for fighting Titans.
Why are they looking at me like that?
What is this?
Information We Can Share So Far:
The Survey Corps (1)
Their primary mission consists of
reconnoitering outlying areas.
Their objectives have changed
following the Fall of Wall Maria.
Information We Can Share So Far:
The Survey Corps (2)
After the Fall, their new objective is to
prepare for the second operation to
recapture Wall Maria by establishing
supply points and routes for troop movement.
Wall Rose Interior
Trainees, keep your equipment
at hand, and stand by!
And then...
We managed to get some gas,
and retreat from Trost.
So that's what happened...
I'm sorry.
I requested supplies
for everyone many times, but...
And we finally managed
to get some gas, too.
Th-Then does that mean that
everyone who isn't here...
Yeah.
Even Mikasa?
N-No...
I thought Mikasa came back
later with Jean and the rest.
Jean, don't tell me Mikasa was injured.
Hey, what's wrong?
We've been ordered to keep it a secret.
I can't discuss it.
Keep it a secret?
What?
Of course, it won't stay secret for long...
Before long, all humanity
will know about it.
Assuming humanity lasts that long....
A fortification of flesh, made from Titans.
The engineers are pretty smart.
But we can't lower our guard.
We stand at the front lines of the war
between humanity and the Titans...
at the precipice.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
It won't interfere with the mission.
But I'm worried about my
friends in the vanguard.
The messenger I just saw on
his way to HQ looked pale.
Yeah,
but we simply need to fend off
the Titans, just as we trained.
Captain Hannes, I heard that the three
children who escaped with you
five years ago are trainees now.
Were they in the vanguard?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have said anything.
They're safe.
They're tough.
Each possesses a means of survival.
One excels in combat.
One has formidable resolve.
And one has a brilliant mind.
They're safe.
I know they've survived.
Trainee Jaeger!
As well as Trainees Ackerman and Arlert...
What you're doing right now
is an act of treason!
We may decide to kill you on the spot!
If you attempt to lie to us,
or make a single move,
we will fire an HE Projectile at you immediately.
We will not hesitate!
Huh?
Answer me at once!
What are you?!
Are you a man? Or a Titan?
What kind of question is that?
Why look at me like that?
Looking at me
as if I'm a monster...
Is that what they think I am?
I d-don't understand the question!
He's pretending to know nothing?
Monster!
Try that again, and I'll blow you to pieces.
It just takes an instant!
You won't have time to reveal your true form!
True form?
Plenty of people saw you,
as you emerged from within a Titan!
Humanity has permitted an unknown
creature like you to infiltrate Wall Rose!
Even if you are trainees
given to us by the King,
the safest course is to
eliminate the risk immediately!
My thinking is correct!
The Armored Titan that destroyed Wall
Maria could appear at any minute.
Right now, humanity is at risk of annihilation!
Do you understand?
We can't waste more time or troops on you!
I will fire an HE Projectile
at you without hesitation!
It's true that they aren't being cooperative.
We aren't likely to get
any useful information out of them.
You're right, Sir.
We're wasting time and troops.
Captain, this is our chance!
If we dismember him while he
pretends to be human...
My specialty is
tearing through flesh.
If necessary, I am willing to
demonstrate at any time.
If anyone would like to experience it firsthand,
I invite them to be the first to approach.
Captain, Mikasa Ackerman was
in the rearguard with us.
She is worth a hundred other soldiers.
Her loss would be a critical blow to humanity.
Hey...
Mikasa... Armin!
What's going on here?
Mikasa!
You can't fight another human!
Where could we run
within these cramped walls?
It doesn't matter who I must fight.
I won't let anyone kill Eren.
I don't need any other reason.
Let's talk this through!
No one knows what's going on,
so they're ruled by fear!
Am I the only one who thinks I'm not a Titan?
Damn it.
I don't remember how I got here!
I'm too exhausted to move,
and if I say anything, they'll probably kill me.
Killed by a human?
That's ridiculous!
What is this about, anyway?
I came out of a Titan?
What are they talking about?!
What the hell is going on?!
Wasn't that a dream?
If it wasn't...
Then my arm regrew where
my clothes are missing...
That'd make me just like a Titan!
That's impossible...
Why would I...
Why?
I'll ask you once more!
What are you?!
I can't screw up my answer...
I wouldn't be the only one to die.
That's right.
I've always been
just like everyone else...
A human!
I see...
Then don't hate me for this.
There's no avoiding it.
No one can prove
that they are not the devil.
Eren! Armin!
We're going up!
Stop!
Eren...
When I get back,
I'll show you what I've kept secret
in the basement all this time.
Never let go of this key.
And every time you see it,
remember that you must
go to the basement!
This shot will impair your memory.
That's why I can't explain now...
Listen to me.
Take back Wall Maria and reach the basement.
This power will help you then!
Their memories will tell you how to use it.
Eren!
If you get to the basement someday,
you'll learn the truth...
The path will be harsh and cruel,
but you must make it there!
If you want to save Mikasa,
Armin, and everyone else,
you must master this power!
Did we get him?
No...
Your dreams are where your heart is
They're more fragile than life itself
Over and over you cast them aside,
only to find more
Now, rest in peace
Pounding impulses defile the things we wish for
and the more we forget
the more we remember again
In this beautiful, cruel world
all I can do is ask why we're still alive
Oh, with our strength--and our weakness--
what are we going to protect if there's no sense
to anything anymore?
"Eren is not an enemy of humanity."
Armin puts his life on the line
to plead for Eren.
However, consumed by terror,
the Garrison is incapable of rational thought
and orders Eren's execution.
Response
The Battle for Trost (6)